Hello everyone, Good morning and greetings to all.
哈囉大家好，早安
Today I'm gonna talk about Web Hosting Server using Ubuntu and Cyberpanel
今天我要談談使用 Ubuntu 和 Cyber​​panel 的虛擬主機伺服器
But let me introduce myself first. My name is Darian Rizaludin
但讓我先自我介紹一下。我叫Darian Rizaludin
Bussiness development at Radnet Digital Indonesia
Radnet Digital Indonesia 的業務發展
I'm in the web and hosting division
我在網絡和託管部門
So I often doing things related to Linux administration servers and network
所以我經常做與Linux管理服務器和網路相關的事情
Let's start with Cyberpanel first.
讓我們先從 Cyber​​panel 開始。
Cyberpanel is a control panel of OpenLiteSpeed...
Cyber​​panel 是 OpenLiteSpeed 的控制面板...
that you can manage your websites, install Wordpress and more
你可以管理你的網站、安裝 Wordpress 等
but with this Cyberpanel, you can do so much things with one click like
但是有了這個 Cyber​​panel，你可以一鍵完成很多事情，像是
install WordPress and then
安裝 WordPress 然後
set up SSL, make many other webistes,
設置 SSL，製作許多其他的網站，
change PHP version up to version 8 and also
更改PHP 版本，最高到版本 8 ，以及
using the File Manager which is built-in feature in Cyberpanel.
使用 Cyber​​panel 內建的文件管理器。
I simply recommend this for those who want
對於那些希望簡易的人來說
to keep it easy and simple.
我十分推薦這個
What is OpenLiteSpeed then?
那什麼是 OpenLiteSpeed？
It is one of the fastest web server.
它是最快的網路伺服器之一
You don't need to be confused of the differences between OpenLiteSpeed and Lite Speed.
你不用困惑 OpenLiteSpeed 和 Lite Speed 之間的差異
All have the same function
他們有相同的功能
and it's open source too.
而且它也是開源的
So you can install OpenLiteSpeed on a vps server
所以你可以在跑著 Ubuntu 20.04
that is running on Ubuntu 20.04 or on
或 CentOS 8 的 vps 伺服器上
CentOS 8
安裝 OpenLiteSpeed
So when you install the Cyberpanel on a vps,
當你在 vps 上安裝 Cyber​​panel 時，
there will be a web interface to control OpenLiteSpeed
會有一個 Web 界面來控制 OpenLiteSpeed
There is also a plugin in Cyberpanel called LSCache.
Cyber​​panel 中還有一個插件叫做 LSCache。
It is actually a built in OpenLiteSpeed cache solution.
它其實是一個內建的 OpenLiteSpeed 緩存解決方案。
It also runs with Apache and NginX server
它也可以與 Apache 和 NginX 伺服器一起運行
but some features can only run on OpenLiteSpeed server
但某些功能只能在 OpenLiteSpeed 伺服器上運行
Now, let's just go ahead. What do you need to prepare
現在，讓我們繼續吧  安裝此 Cyber​​panel 時
when installing this Cyberpanel.
你需要準備什麼？
I have prepared a vps when I writing this slides.
我在準備投影片時準備了一個 vps
So most of them are in default settings.
他們的設定大多都是預設。
We use the port 22 for SSH.
我們將端口 22 用於 SSH。
Now we can access the vps and use it to install.
現在我們可以進入 vps 並使用它進行安裝。
You can use terminal on Ubuntu or
你可以在 Ubuntu 上使用終端機或是
here I give an example using PuTTY
這裡我舉一個使用 PuTTY 的例子
Just access it using user root
使用root用戶進入
then the IP address.
然後是IP位址
This is how it looks when you have successfully connect with SSH.
如果你成功用 SSH 連接會是這個樣子
I am using Ubuntu 20.04.2.
我使用的是 Ubuntu 20.04.2。
This is the first command we need to type to install Cyberpanel
要安裝 Cyber​​panel  這是我們第一個需要輸入的指令
just type this comment and used on ssh that already connect
只需輸入此命令並在已經連接的 ssh 上使用
earlier so we first remotely to SSH using
早些時候我們先使用了終端機或PuTTy
Terminal or PuTTY
來SSH遠端連線
If it successful then type this here too
如果成功的話，也在此處輸入這個
We just need to follow these steps
我們只需要按照這些步驟
If installation is success
如果安裝成功
we will get info like this
我們會得到這樣的訊息
visit https://your server's IP and use the port 8090
"visit https://your server's IP” 並使用端口 8090
It'll also show panel username, panel password, mysql username and mysql password
它還會顯示面板用戶名(Panel username)、面板密碼 (Panel password)、mysql 用戶名(Mysql username)和 mysql 密碼 (Mysql password)
We can update the Cyberpanel and the OpenLiteSpeed
我們可以更新 Cyber​​panel 和 OpenLiteSpeed
Here is a command to upgrade the version
這是升級版本的命令
using the stable OpenLiteSpeed (v1.6)
使用穩定的 OpenLiteSpeed (v1.6)
You can upgrade both
你可以使用以下命令同時升級
This is a command that is used to upgrade
像這個命令是用於升級
Cyberpanel and OpenLiteSpeed. Just copy this and
Cyber​​panel 和 OpenLiteSpeed  只需要複製這個然後
paste to your terminal, and you will be able
貼到你的終端機，你就可以
to update the Cyberpanel and OpenLiteSpeed
更新 Cyber​​panel 和 OpenLiteSpeed
There is also other ways to update OpenLiteSpeed
還有其他方法可以更新 OpenLiteSpeed
to the most recent stable version.
到最新的穩定版本。
Type "apt-get update" first and
首先輸入“apt-get update”
then apt-get upgrade.
然後 apt-get upgrade
Or we can download with other way (tar.gz)
或者我們可以通過其他方式下載 (tar.gz)
After download using wget, we can extract and then move it its folder and install.
使用 wget 下載後，我們可以解壓縮，然後將它移動到其資料夾並安裝
So the first command will update the package automatically
第一個命令會自動更新package
and the second one for update it manually
第二個透過 openlitespeed 網站上提供的
via package that available on the openlitespeed website,
package 來手動更新
I will give an example about how to
我來舉例說明如何
install a website in Cyberpanel
在 Cyber​​panel 中安裝網站
I'll use WordPress for a simple example.
我用 WordPress 作一個簡單的例子。
First we have to point to the available DNS records
首先我們必須指向可用的 DNS 記錄
In my case, I'm using digital ocean for the vps
在我的例子  我是使用DigitalOcean的vps
I pointing my domain to the digitalocean's public IP.
我把我的網域指向 DigitalOcean 的公共 IP
After successfully pointing the domain, then access the Cyberpanel
成功指向網域後
by accessing the http://IP address plus
再透過訪問 http:// (IP 位址) 加上端口 8090
port 8090. Just like that.
進入Cyber​​panel  就像這樣
Well this is his cyberpanel login view.
這是Cyberpanel登入畫面
Type the username and the password.
輸入用戶名稱和密碼
If we forget the Cyberpanel password
如果忘記了 Cyber​​panel 密碼
We can use command
可以使用指令
sudo cat .litespeed_password
sudo cat .litespeed_password
Here we can see the stored username and password
在這裡我們可以看到儲存的用戶名稱和密碼
You can use that comment in case you forget.
如果你忘記了就可以使用這個指令
This is when successfully logged in on the dashboard panel,
這是在控制面板上成功登入後的樣子
we can go to the website here, we click the
我們可以到網站的頁面  點擊
website button to start then we click create website.
"Website" 來開始然後我們點擊 ”create website”
Now, we're going to use Default mode.
現在，我們要使用預設模式
enter your domain email and PHP version that
輸入您的網域、電子郵件和要使用的PHP 版本
we will use
選擇擁有者、選擇管理員、網域
Select owner, choose Admin, domain, then email your email address and the PHP version we will use.
然後電子郵件地址和我們要使用的 PHP 版本。
There is also optional feature like SSL
還有像 SSL 這樣的額外選項
and DKIM for email security.
和用於電子郵件安全性的 DKIM。
Here is the interface. Fill up this form
這是界面  填寫此表格
from select package, select on owner, domain name, email
選擇 package、選擇擁有者、網域名、電子郵件
and what PHP version will we use then tick DKIM support and SSL
還有我們將使用的 PHP 版本然後勾選 DKIM 支援 和 SSL
Then click Create Website
然後點擊創建網站 (create website)
Now after successfully creating an account
現在成功創完建立網站的帳號後
for website, then next we will
接下來我們要
install WordPress on the that account
用應用安裝程式
that we created earlier using the installer application,
在此帳號安裝 WordPress
so the application installer already include WordPress and LSCache.
應用安裝程式(application installer)已經包含 WordPress 和 LSCache
We are going to install WordPress with the addition of the LSCache feature in php 8
我們要使用  LSCache 額外 php 8功能來安裝 WordPress
Now we fill in the blog, blog title, login user and the login password
現在我們填寫部落格、部落格標題、登入用戶和登入密碼
what is the email for this.
電子郵件
Leave it blank for path
path 的部分留空
if we have our special folder can fill in the name of the
如果我們有了指定資料夾可以填寫資料夾名稱
folder, if we use default, it's better
如果用預設的
Now, this is how it looks, click install now, if you are sure of the
現在，這是它的外觀 ，如果你確定輸入的設定
settings that we have entered.
點擊 立即安裝
If it successful we can access it with the domain name slash
如果成功，我們可以使用網域名斜槓
wp-login.php
wp-login.php 來進入
Now, these are the steps for enabling
現在，這些是在Cyberpanel
LetsEncrypt SSL on our Cyberpanel.
啟用LetsEncrypt SSL的步驟
First, we need to make sure that the DNS is properly configured
首先，我們需要用 DNS 檢查器功能
using the DNS checker feature.
確保DNS配置正確
Check it using dnschecker.org
用 dnschecker.org 檢查
After that, just login to our Cyberpanel dashboard.
之後，只需登入我們的 Cyber​​panel 控制板即可
On the left side of the panel, follow these (flow) buttons
在面板的左側，按照這些（流程）按鈕
click menu SSL > manage SSL  > and then select the website that
點擊選單 SSL > 管理 SSL > 然後選擇網站
we want to attach SSL on it and then click the Issus SSL.
我們要在其上附加 SSL，然後點擊 Issus SSL。
Ah, this is tips & trick for LSCache plugin settings.
啊，這是 LSCache 插件設置的提示和技巧
LSCache itself is automatically installed when we success install Wordpress.
當我們成功安裝 Wordpress 時，LSCache 本身會自動安裝
So we can customize the settings.
所以我們可以自訂設定
First, we go to the LSCache setting.
首先，我們到 LSCache 設定
If we want advanced or special settings,
如果我們想要進階或特殊設定
we can set http2 to on then
我們可以將 http2 設定為 on 然後
we can delete the query string then remove wordpress emoji.
我們可以刪除查詢字符串，然後刪除 wordpress 表情符號
etc
等等
We can restore the old Wordpress from another host too
我們也可以從另一個主機復原舊的 Wordpress
but this is not for beginner
但這不適合初學者
because you must understand about SFTP,
因為你必須要先會 SFTP
compressing and extracting Wordpress directory to
將 Wordpress 目錄壓縮並解壓到
So there are several plans to move the new WordPress.
有幾個計劃來移動新的 WordPress
First of all we have to backup
首先我們要備份
using the tools feature.
使用工具功能
After the backup process have been successful, then the backup file needs to be
備份成功後，需要使用 SFTP 伺服器
uploaded to a new one using an SFTP server or
或像是rsync
another thing like rsync.
上傳備份檔案到新的
In the new server, we need to restore but we need to change PHP 8 settings on the
在新伺服器中，我們需要復原但我們需要在manage PHP > Basic >
manage PHP > Basic >
select the version 8.0 >
select the version 8.0 >
更改 PHP 8 上的設定
then increase the post_max_size
然後增加 post_max_size
Because the compressed wordpress will be more than 10 MB.
因為壓縮後的 wordpress 會超過 10 MB
After that it should be successfully restored.
接著它應該就會成功復原
Now in this cyberpanel feature there is also a benchmark.
在Cyberpanel功能中還有一個benchmark
So what we are trying to test is 10,000 clients/second
我們現在是在主頁上測試每秒 10,000 個客戶端
on the homepage and the average time is
平均時間是
100 milliseconds so we can successfully test 20,000 clients per second
100 毫秒  因此前 10 秒
for the first 10 seconds.
我們每秒可以成功測試 20,000 個客戶端
This results look like this.
結果看起來像這樣
Now the second we try to test a total of 10000 clients on the post page
現在第二次測試  我們嘗試在Post page上測試 10000 個客戶端
We try to run the test for 20 seconds and the success rate is 100%.
我們嘗試執行測試 20 秒，成功率為 100%。
so at least we get 10000 hits per
所以在WordPredss我們每秒至少可以有 10000 次點擊
second on our WordPress and use
這是使用DigitalOcean  vps 伺服器的情況
the Ocean digital panel vps server at a price of 5 dollars per month
價格為每月 5 美元，已經足夠用了
that is enough. So actually using Ubuntu for treatment
所以在Ubuntu上進行處理
5 dollars the price is on digitalocean and the test results are
然後在 DigitalOcean 上花5 美元，測試結果是
good (test 1 and test 2). You can try this.
不錯（測試 1 和測試 2）你可以試試看。
Ok. that is all from me.
好的 那這就是全部
Thank you very much. You can contact me by
非常感謝  你可以透過以下方式聯繫我
email: kontak@darian.my.id or instagram
電子郵件：kontak@darian.my.id
Good bye. Thankyou.
謝謝  再見